A Finding Aid to the Philip Evergood Papers, 1890-1971, in the Archives of American Art AAA.everphil
Archives of American Art
Philip Evergood papers
1890-1971
AAA.everphil
Archives of American Art
12 Linear feet
The papers of painter Philip Evergood measure 12 linear feet and date from 1890 to 1971. Found within the papers are biographical materials; personal and business correspondence; writings, including essays, lectures, speeches, and sound recordings of radio appearances; subject files; personal business records; printed material; scrapbooks; artwork, including oil paintings, sketches, and childhood drawings; and photographs of Evergood, his family and friends, and his work.
Evergood, Philip, 1901-1973
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Philip Evergood donated his papers to the Archives in 1971. Additional materials were donated in 1974 by Evergood's wife, Julia Cross Evergood. In 1977, two typescripts of essays were donated by Abram Lerner.
Related Archival Materials note
Also found in the Archives of American Art are Letters from Philip Evergood; Gael Hammer letters relating to Miles and Philip Evergood; an oral history interview with Philip Evergood by Forrest Selvig, December 3, 1968; and Philip Evergood interview with John I.H. Baur, June 1959.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Portions of this collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 429-430, 1345-1355, 439, 2162, 2223, 1885, and 2804 at the Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the papers as described in this finding aid does not reflect the order of the collection on microfilm due to reprocessing and not all of the collection is on microfilm. Some of the sound recordings in this collection have been copied for research access and digital copies are available in the Archives of American Art offices.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Biographical/Historical note
Painter and printmaker Philip Evergood (1901-1973) lived and worked in New York City and Bridgewater, Connecticut and was known as an expressionist and social realist who incorporated elements of the fantastic into his works. A native New Yorker, Evergood's father, Miles Blashki, was a Polish-Australian artist, and his mother, Flora Jane Perry, was English. At his mother's insistence, Evergood attended boarding schools in England and graduated from Eton in 1919. He left Cambridge University to pursue art studies at London's Slade School of Fine Arts and returned to America in 1923 to study with George Luks at the Art Students League.
In 1927, Evergood held his first one man show at New York's Dudensing Gallery and continued to travel back and forth between France, Spain, and America throughout the 1920s. In 1931, he married dancer and actress Julia Cross and found work as a muralist and painter for the WPA Federal Arts Project in the early 1930s. From 1937-1938, he served as president of the New York Artists Union and, along with other social realist painters, joined Herman Baron's stable at the ACA (American Contemporary Art) Gallery, where he exhibited several one man shows during the late 1930s and 1940s.
During the 1940s and 1950s, Evergood was a popular lecturer and taught at art schools, including the Skowhegan School, and began producing large scale lithographs and etchings along with his paintings. While working as a picture framer for additional income, he met the art collector Joseph Hirshhorn who would purchase 10 artworks at their first meeting and become a life long patron. He continued to exhibit his work at the ACA Gallery and the annual contemporary shows of major museums, such as the Carnegie Institute and the Art Institute of Chicago. Evergood exhibited in over 35 exhibitions, including a retrospective at the Whitney Museum in 1960, and died in a house fire in Bridgewater in 1973.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter Philip Evergood measure 12 linear feet and date from 1890 to 1971. Found within the papers are biographical materials; personal and business correspondence; writings, including essays, lectures, speeches, and sound recordings of radio appearances; subject files; personal business records; printed material; scrapbooks; artwork, including oil paintings, sketches, and childhood drawings; and photographs of Evergood, his family and friends, and his work.
Biographical materials include curriculum vitae, forms, memberships, and the contact information of friends and acquaintances. Correspondence is with business associates and artists, including Charles Edward Smith, Rockwell Kent, Frank Kleinholz, Leon Kroll, Joan Miro, and Yasuo Kuniyoshi. Writings consist primarily of Evergood's artist statements, essays, lectures and speeches, as well as notes, transcripts, and recordings of broadcast radio shows. Subject files focus on art institutions and organizations, funding opportunities, and political topics of personal interest.
Personal business records include artist lists, contracts with galleries, and banking and estate records. Printed materials include clippings, four clippings scrapbooks, exhibition catalogs, and periodicals with articles featuring Evergood. There are loose sketches and mixed media, including oils and watercolors, of Evergood's artwork. Photographs are of Evergood, his friends and family, and photographs and negatives of his artwork.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1930-1971 (0.2 linear feet; Box 1, OV 13)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1930-1970 (3.5 linear feet; Boxes 1-4)
Series 3: Writings, 1905-1970 (1.7 linear feet; Boxes 4-5)
Series 4: Subject Files, 1919-1971 (0.7 linear feet; Boxes 5-6)
Series 5: Personal Business Records, 1902-1970 (0.5 linear feet; Box 6)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1914-1970 (2.3 linear feet; Boxes 7-9, 11)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1924-1954 (0.6 linear feet; Boxes 11-12)
Series 8: Artwork, 1905-1970 (1.4 linear feet; Box 9, OV 14-20, RD 23)
Series 9: Photographic Materials, 1890-1970 (1.1 linear feet; Boxes 9-10, OV 21-22)
Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; Kleinholz, Frank, 1901-; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974; Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1889-1953; Miró, Joan, 1893-; Smith, Charles Edward, 1904-1970; Art, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Artists--Political activity; Interviews; Oil paintings; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sketches; Sound recordings; Transcripts; Watercolors
- Biographical Materials, 1930-1971; Series 1; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1, OV 13
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials include an award certificate, curriculum vitae, forms, art memberships, contact information of friends and acquaintances, and information on Evergood's parents.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are arranged by document type.
  - Award, National Academy of Design, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Forms, circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Medical Records, circa 1941-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memberships, circa 1934-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Names and Addresses, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
    Oversized material housed in OV 13.
  - Evergood, Miles and Flora (parents), circa 1950-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Names and Addresses from Box 1, Folder 7, circa 1930-1970 (Box OV 13)
- Correspondence, 1930-1970; Series 2; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-4
  Correspondence includes incoming and outgoing letters to friends, artists, and business colleagues regarding Evergood's art commissions and sales, art classes, and political and war related activities. The series also includes untranslated letters written in Russian.
  Materials are arranged in chronological order. Letters arranged alphabetically by recipient are undated.
  - Written in Russian, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adessa - Baur to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beal - Butler to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cahill - Dyson to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Eastman - Futerman to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gallo - Guston to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Haff - Kiuiti to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Larkins - Moran to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Neuberger - Prestopino to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rabinowitz - Rosenbloom to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Russell - Sykes to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Taylor - Zorach to Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Abraham - Keppel from Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Larkin - Wight from Evergood, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified, Alphabetical by First Name, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Chronological, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 26-30)
  - Chronological, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 31-39)
  - Chronological, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Chronological, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Chronological, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9-18)
  - Chronological, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 19-27)
  - Chronological, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 28-34)
  - Chronological, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 35-42)
  - Chronological, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1-9)
  - Chronological, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 10-17)
  - Chronological, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 18-23)
  - Chronological, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24-30)
  - Chronological, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31-40)
  - Chronological, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 41-45)
  - Chronological, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - Chronological, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5-14)
  - Chronological, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15-22)
  - Envelopes with Notations, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
  - Duplicates, circa 1930-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Writings, 1905-1970; Series 3; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Writings consist of Evergood's artist statements and over 45 essays, lectures, and speeches that cover topics ranging from social justice and artist responsibilities to a survey of recent art history. In addition, the series includes eulogies of close friends, poetry, and miscellaneous notes and writings. There are also 6 broadcast radio recordings and other miscellaneous sound recordings featuring Philip Evergood from the 1930s and 1940s, and a lecture of Maxim Karolik's 1963 lecture "Collecting With a Purpose, For What?" Recordings are on sound discs and sound tape reels (1/4 inch).
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  Many of the sound recordings have been digitized for research access.
  - Artist Statements, circa 1945-1962 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Artist Statements, Autobiographical, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Artist Statements, On America and Art World, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Artist Statements, On Art and Artists, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Artist Statements, On Specific Paintings, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Assignments and Childhood Compositions, circa 1905-1910 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Book Review, On Hermitage Museum, Leningrad, circa 1961 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Broadcast, Jean Colbert Show (interview), circa 1940-1970; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate; 1 Sound discs (lacquer) Original (Box 4, Folder 34)
    Original sound disc housed separately, see SIRIS for location.
    Digital sound file is access copy.
  - Broadcast, Radio Station (transcript), circa 1938 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Broadcast, School Art League Radio (notes), 1944 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Broadcast, WABC-FM Radio Station (notes), circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Broadcast, WABC-FM Radio Station, Living Art, 1942; 2 Sound discs (lacquer) Original; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Original sound discs housed separately, see SIRIS for location.
  - Broadcast, WNYC Radio Station (transcript), circa 1937-1945 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Broadcast, WNYC Radio Station (speech), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Broadcast, WNYC Radio Station (transcript), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    With transit commissioner Haskell and Judge Goldstein.
  - Broadcast, WNYC Radio Station, Art in New York, 1944; 1 sound tape reels Original (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Philip Evergood on the show with Frank Kleinholz.
  - Broadcast, WQXR Radio Station, 1938; 1 Sound discs (aluminum) Original; 1 sound tape reels Includes transcript. Duplicate (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Philip Evergood with Edith Bry; original sound disc housed separately, see SIRIS for location.
  - Bulletin, American Art Congress, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Essay, "American Artist Wants Peace", circa 1939 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Essay, "Does An Artist Need a Live Model?", 1948 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Essay, "Fundamentals, Functions, Frameworks of Art", 1944 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Essay, "New Idea in Art Training", circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Essay, "Resident Artist", circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Essay, "Social Art Today", 1944 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Essay, "Social Content in Art", circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Essay, "Take Your Choice", 1953 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Essay, On Art and Artistic Tradition, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Essay, On Artists and McCarthyism, circa 1950-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Essay, On Artists and Society, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Essays, On Parents, circa 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Essay, On Rockwell Kent, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Essay, On Russian Artists and War, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Eulogies, For Artists and Friends, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lecture, Bridgewater Library, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lecture, Lions Club, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lecture, Michigan State University, "Conversation with the Artist", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Lecture, Minnesota University, circa 1950-1970; 1 sound tape reels Original (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lecture, Philadelphia Museum School, "Role of Government in Art", 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lecture, W.P.A. Art Center (Queens, NY), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Poetry, circa 1925-1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Preface, Booklet by Elizabeth McCausland, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Preface, Brochure (United American Artists), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Prefaces, Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Press Conference, Rockefeller Center, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Press Release, Artist Housing Committee, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Speech, American Artists' Congress (Carnegie Hall), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Speech, Artists' Union (CIO Charter), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Speech, Brooklyn Museum, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Speech, Butler Art Institute (jury award), 1947; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate; 1 Sound discs (lacquer) Original (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Commentary by Lee Leonard; original sound disc housed separately, see SIRIS for location.
  - Speech, Deerfield Valley Art Association, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Speech, Fairfield Union Hall, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Speech, Federal Art Gallery (exhibition opening), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Speech, Gallery 63 (exhibition opening), circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Speech, Iowa State Teachers College, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Speech, Iowa University, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Speeches, Kalamazoo College, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Speech, Kansas State Teachers College, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Speech, "Last Ten Years in American Art", circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Speech, Manhattan Center, "Artist Fights Back", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Speech, Mural Craft Meeting, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Speech, Museum of Modern Art, "What is American Art?", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Speech, Russian War Relief War Calendar, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Speech, Third Woodstock Art Conference, "Artist and the Museum", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Speech, United American Artists (rally), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Speeches, Exhibition Openings, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Speech, For Mexican Fiesta (benefit), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Speech, On Artists, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Speech, On Austin-Mahoney Bill (NY state legislation), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Speech, On Great Art as People's Art, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Speech, On Mural Painting, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Speeches, On World's Fair, circa 1940-1960 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Symposium, Artists Congress, "What Art Means to Us", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Symposium, Fine Arts Panel, "Artist as Interpreter [of] His Age", circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Symposium, Hotel Woodstock, "What Are the Artist's Social Commitments?", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Symposium, Independents Society Exhibition, "How Can the Artist Reach His Public?", circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous Speech Fragments and Notes for Speeches, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - By Others, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5)
    - Bauer, John, Monograph, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Biddle, George, Catalog Translation, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Green, Ruth, "Such a Day in New York", circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Karolik, Maxim, "Collecting With a Purpose, For What?", 1963; 3 sound tape reels Original (Box 5, Folder 56-57)
    - Lowry, W. McNeil, "Arts and Philanthropy", 1962 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Page, Joseph, "Report on Notes on the Liber Studorium", circa 1950-1970 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Somers, James H., "Journey Without a Destination", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Valente, Alfredo, "Philip Evergood", circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Unknown, On the Bridge of Life, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Miscellaneous Poetry, Essays, and Fragments, circa 1950-1970 (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Subject Files, 1919-1971; Series 4; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  Subject files focus on art institutions and organizations Evergood had established working relationships with; schools Evergood had attended or taught at; potential funding opportunities; and political topics of interest, particularly those related to peace or social justice. Filed materials include annotated mailings, invitations, newsletters, bulletins, and other printed material.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by institutional name or topic.
  - ACA Gallery, circa 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Art Students League of New York, circa 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Artist Directories, circa 1950-1970 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Artist Groups, circa 1935-1970 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Artists Equity Association, circa 1945-1970 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Brooklyn Museum, circa 1951-1966 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Competitions and Entry Forms, circa 1945-1970 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Congressional Legislation, circa 1959-1970 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Cooper Union, 1948-1964 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Educational Alliance, circa 1945-1970 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Eton College, circa 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 74-75)
  - Foundation Funding, circa 1950-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Jefferson School, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mail Order Announcements, circa 1945-1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Academy of Design, circa 1960-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, circa 1948-1952 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, circa 1965-1970 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Political/Social Justice, circa 1945-1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Print Council of America, circa 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Schools/Universities, circa 1940-1970 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Skowhegan School, circa 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Trinity Hall College, circa 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Vietnam War, circa 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - War Contribution/Peace Efforts, circa 1940-1950 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Whitney Museum, circa 1950-1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Workshop School, circa 1950-1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Personal Business Records, 1902-1970; Series 5; 0.5 Linear feet Box 6
  Personal business records include artist lists, contracts with galleries, banking and estate records, and miscellaneous art and shipping receipts.
  - Lists of Works, circa 1930-1970 (Box 6, Folder 20-24)
  - Contracts, Galleries, circa 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Contracts, Insurance, circa 1951-1968 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Contracts, Residences, circa 1952-1964 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Income Taxes, 1952-1966 (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
  - Receipts, Shipping, circa 1940-1970 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Receipts, Stocks, circa 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Receipts, Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1970 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Wills, 1902-1964 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1940-1970 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Printed Material, 1914-1970; Series 6; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 7-9, 11
  Printed material consists primarily of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and art or news related periodicals with articles featuring Evergood. Some clippings are in Russian. Additional printed materials are filed in subject files.
  - Book, Lindsay, Sally, Figure Skating, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Booklet, Perry, George, Assuan Dam: Iron and Steel Work, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, Flyers, and Programs, circa 1940-1970 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Bulletins, 1941-1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, circa 1930-1970 (Box 7, Folder 7-10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 1.
  - Clippings, 1932-1945 (Box 7, Folder 11-16)
  - Clippings, 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 17-20)
  - Clippings, 1951-1964 (Box 7, Folder 21-25)
  - Clippings, 1965-1970 (Box 7, Folder 26-28)
  - Clippings (Russian), circa 1940-1970 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1935-1970 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1935-1960 (Box 7, Folder 31-34)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1961-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Other Artists (group shows), circa 1935-1965 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Other Artists (individual shows), circa 1935-1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Invitations, circa 1935-1970 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Periodicals, Art Digest, 1941-1952 (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Periodicals, Art Gallery, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Periodicals, Art News, 1941-1951 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
  - Periodicals, Carnegie Magazine, 1943-1949 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Periodicals, Magazine of Art, 1941-1952 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Periodicals, MKR's Art Outlook, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Periodicals, New Masses, 1942-1947 (Box 8, Folder 19-21)
  - Periodicals, New Yorker, 1941, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Periodicals, Newsweek, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Periodicals, Time, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Periodicals, Miscellaneous A, circa 1945-1970 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Periodicals, Miscellaneous B--L, circa 1945-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 1. Two items, Life magazine trays, housed in artifact cabinet.
  - Periodicals, Miscellaneous M-N, circa 1945-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Periodicals, Miscellaneous O-Z, circa 1945-1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Postcards, circa 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 7, Folder 7, circa 1930-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Periodicals from Box 9, Folder 1, circa 1945-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1924-1954; Series 7; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 11-12
  Four clippings scrapbooks document Evergood's activities with the American Artists Congress and critical reaction to WPA and PWAP art during the 1920s and 1930s.